Yes Jay

Sadhasivam Jayabalaganesan

SUMMARY

Director | Platform engineering

Fluid technologist specialized in architecting eCommerce technology stacks. Deep-rooted understanding of eCommerce strategies, Payment Gateways, Engineering practices, Startup Culture, Strategic approaches, Cross Culture infrastructure detailing. Passion for Developer Experience, Product Management, and Developer Relations. Love Building Tools.

EXPERIENCE

FedEx | Dataworks

Jan 2021 - Present | Area leader | Supplychain platform

- Mapped Shoprunner eCommerce domain artifacts with FedEx Dataworks shipping domain for the next-generation solution and reduced technical risk
- Leading Dataworks Supply Chain platform to maximize pre & post-purchase expreince. Increase visibility between the buyer, the seller, and the shipper relationship.
- Part of Dataworks Strategic engagement group in leading vendor outreach and collaboration process to provide high-quality integration.

Shoprunner Inc.

Apr 2011 - Present | Principal Engineering | Shoprunner

- Helped shoprunner from the early stage and witnessed the FedEx merger
- Led Shoprunnner Data platform and built a robust data pipeline to ingest data for downstream analytics and machine-learning work
- Led shoprunner channel partners integration with American Express, Chase, e.t.c and acquired a million members.

EDUCATION

Anna University

1995 – 1999 | Computer Science Engineering (B.Tech)

OUTREACH

- @ sadhasivam@gmail.com
- +1 610-483-7859
- In linkedin 7
- github
 ¬
- Chester Springs, PA

STRENGTHS

Organizational Leadership		API Development		Advocacy
Process Improvement D		etail Oriented	Delivery Focused	
Agile/Scrum Software Development >20 yrs				

TECHNOLOGIES



A DAY IN MY LIFE



ERSTWHILE ASSOCIATIONS

- ightarrow Society of Automotive Engineers (SAE) (5 years) ightarrow
- > Manugistics Supply Chain (Now Blue Yonder) (5 years) >
- > Cognizant Services (> 1 year) ↗
- > Toyota eLearning (worked in Japan) (> 1 Year)